[
        {
        "id": 1,
        "question": "What is React or ReactJS?",
        "answers" : [
            "Component-based Javascript library", "Javascript framework","Javascript file", "None of the above"
        ],
         "correct" : "Component-based Javascript library"
    },
    {
        "id": 2,
        "question": "Which of the following comes under the advantages of React?",
        "answers" : [
            "Integration with other frameworks (like BackboneJS, Angular, etc.) becomes easier because it is only a view library", "Increases the performance of an application using Virtual DOM", "Can render both on server and client side", "All of the above"
        ],
         "correct" : "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "id": 3,
        "question": "The number of elements that can be returned by a valid React component is ______.",
        "answers" : [
            "5","1", "3", "2"
        ],
         "correct" : "1"
    },
    {
        "id": 4,
        "question": "What is the declarative approach for rendering a dynamic list of components depending on array values?",
        "answers" : [
          " Using <Each/> component", "Using reduce array method", "Using Array.map() method", "Using for or while loop"
        ],
         "correct" : "Using Array.map() method"
    },
    {
        "id": 5,
        "question": "The Keys given to a list of elements in React should be ______.",
        "answers" : [
          " Not necessarily unique", "Unique among the siblings only", "Unique in the DOM (Document Object Model)", "None of the above"
        ],
         "correct" : "Unique among the siblings only"
    },
    {
        "id": 6,
        "question": "What is meant by the state in React?",
        "answers" : ["Internal storage of component", "External storage of component", "Permanent storage", "None of the above"
        ],
         "correct" : "Internal storage of component"
    },
    {
        "id": 7,
        "question": "Which command can be used for the creation of React app?",
        "answers" : [
           " npm install create-react-app", "install -g create-react-app", "npm install create-react-app", "None of the above"
        ],
         "correct" : "npm install create-react-app"
    },
    {
        "id": 8,
        "question": "What is used for passing the data to a component from outside?",
        "answers" : [
           "Render with arguments", "setState", "PropTypes", "props"
        ],
         "correct" : "props"
    },
    {
        "id": 9,
        "question": "______ will help to keep the data unidirectional in React.",
        "answers" : [
            "Dom", "Props", "JSX", "Flux"
        ],
         "correct" : "Flux"
    },
    {
        "id": 10,
        "question": "What function will permit for rendering the React content in an HTML page?",
        "answers" : [
          " React.render()", "ReactDOM.start()", "React.mount()", "ReactDOM.render()"
        ],
         "correct" : "ReactDOM.render()"
    }

]